Guide to the Hettie Jones Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Hettie Jones Papers,
1895-2009
[Bulk dates: 1958-2009]
Jones, Hettie.
26.5 linear ft. (62 boxes: 55 document boxes, 3 note card boxes, 2 record cartons, 1 video tape box, 1 over-sized box)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
MS#1513
7451336
The Hettie Jones Papers contains correspondence, writings, and teaching materials related to Hettie Jones' career as a writer, editor, and teacher in the New York City Beat and Downtown literary scene, from the 1960s through the 2000s. Included are manuscripts from Jones' numerous books of poetry and children's and young adult novels, as well as her 1990 autobiography, How I Became Hettie Jones. The collection also features materials from her time as co-editor of Totem Press and Yugen literary journal. A small amount of material pertaining to Jones' former husband, the poet LeRoi Jones/Amiri Baraka, including unpublished early manuscripts and photographs is also here.
Biographical Note
Hettie Jones (nee Cohen, 1934- ) was a major figure in the New York literary avant-garde of the 1950s and 1960s. Born in Brooklyn and raised in Queens, Jones returned to New York City after attending Mary Washington College, then the women's college of the University of Virginia. She found work as an editorial and clerical assistant at Partisan Review and lived in the East Village. Alongside her husband LeRoi Jones (later Amiri Baraka)--with whom she had two children, Kellie and Lisa--she edited and produced the Downtown little magazine, Yugen, which published such seminal poets and writers as Allen Ginsberg, Jack Kerouac, Diane DiPrima, and Charles Olson. Later Jones wrote and published her own poetry and fiction, which has recently garnered critical acclaim. In 1999 Jones received the Poetry Society of America's Norma Farber First Book Award for her collection Drive.
Jones is perhaps best known for her memoir, How I Became Hettie Jones, which provides a detailed portrait of the Downtown and Beat literary scene of the 1950s and 1960s, as well as of her marriage to, and divorce from, African American poet LeRoi Jones, and the difficulties of an interracial relationship in the Civil Rights era.
Jones has been a prolific writer, producing a number of poetry collections including Drive, For Four Hetties, All Told, and Doing Seventy. Much of her writing has been for youth, and she has written many children and young adult novels and non-fiction books, such as ig Star Fallin' Mama, Five Women in Black Music (honored by the New York Public Library), and From Midnight to Dawn. With Rita Marley, the widow of reggae singer Bob Marley, Jones authored the memoir No Woman No Cry.
Jones also served as the Chair of the PEN Prison Writing Committee, subsequently editing two poetry collections derived from workshops she taught at the Bedford Hills Correctional Facility, More In than Out and Aliens at the Border. Having spent much of her professional life teaching creative writing at New York City area colleges and universities, Jones currently teaches in the graduate program in creative writing at The New School, as well as at New York's 92nd Street Y Poetry Center.
Scope and Content
The Hettie Jones Papers include the manuscripts of many of Jones' books, poetry, and short fiction, including multiple drafts of Jones' autobiography How I Became Hettie Jones, as well as her various poetry collections and children's books. The collection contains a number of items related to LeRoi Jones/Amiri Baraka, including unpublished poems, letters, and photographs. There is also extensive correspondence of Jones with many key poets and writers of the New York literary scene and beyond, as well as photographs depicting Downtown and Bohemian life in postwar New York.
The correspondence represents over fifty years of Jones' life, ranging from letters and notes from recognizable figures in the Beat/Downtown arts and jazz scene, to a large amount of communication with Jones' daughters, Kellie and Lisa, and other family members. There is also correspondence between Jones and her former husband, poet LeRoi Jones/Amiri Baraka.
The manuscript series contains Jones' published and unpublished poetry and fiction, manuscript drafts of many of her children's/young adult novels, and various drafts of How I Became Hettie Jones. Also included in this series are items pertaining to Jones' work as editor of Yugen literary magazine.
A large segment of the collection consists of material related to Jones' teaching at various New York City colleges, universities, and prisons, including syllabi, lesson plans, and student work. Much of this material is restricted.
This collection also holds material about the Cohen family, including original immigration and naturalization documents of Jones' relatives from the late Nineteenth and early Twentieth Century, as well as items from Jones' high school and university education. The personal and family materials series also contains photographs, documents, and unpublished writings of Jones' former husband LeRoi Jones/Amiri Baraka.
Also within this collection are audio/visual material, recordings, featuring readings by Jones and other poets, and photos of Jones' family and 'bohemian' life in New York's Lower East Side in the Fifties and Sixties.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in seven series:
Series I: Correspondence, 1940s-2009
Series II: Writings, 1956-2009
Subseries II.1: How I Became Hettie Jones, 1983-2007
Subseries II.2: Poetry, 1950s-2008
Subseries II.3: Prose, 1955-2009
Subseries II.4: Children's Literature, 1971-2002
Subseries II.5: Yugen and Totem Press Material, 1958-1963
Series III: Personal and Family Materials, 1895-2009
Series IV: Printed Materials, 1948-2003
Series V: Teaching Materials, 1982-2009
Subseries V.1: Prison Teaching, 1982-2008
Subseries V.2: University Teaching and Community Workshops, 1984-2009
Series VI: Audio, Visual, and Photographic Material, 1918-2000s
Series VII: LeRoi Jone/Amiri Baraka Material, 1940s-2004
Subjects
Baraka, Imamu Amiri, 1934-; Jones, Hettie; Beat Generation.; Beat Generation--Fiction.; Bohemianism.; Counterculture.; Hippies.; Little Magazines.; Poetry, Modern--20th century.; Poetry, Modern--20th century--Periodicals.; Poetry--Publishing.; Poetry--Social Aspects.; Poets, American--20th century--Biography.; Poets, American--20th century--Correspondence.; Race relations in literature.; Brochures
Access Restrictions
This collection is located primarily off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room. Boxes 55, 57, 58, 60, and 63 are shelved onsite in the Rare Book & Manuscript Library.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
Jones, Hettie Gift, 2009/10/22 2009-2010-M037
Jones, Hettie
Selected Related Material-- At Columbia
Beat Poetry and Papers, Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Columbia University
Kulchur Foundation Records, Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Columbia University
Selected Related Material-- Other Repositories
Amiri Baraka Collection, Syracuse University
Amiri Baraka Collection of Unpublished Poetry, new York Public Library
Carol Berge Papers, University of Texas—Harry Ransom Humanities Research Center
Christopher Felver Portraits of Poets, Authors, and Artists, The Bancroft Library, University oCalifornia, Berkeley
Diane Di Prima Papers, Syracuse University
(Everett) LeRoi Jones (aka Amiri Baraka) Papers, Syracuse University
Imamu Amiri Baraka Manuscripts [ca. 1974-1979], New York Public Library
Literary Correspondence and Manuscript Collection, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series I: Correspondence, 1940s-2009
  This series contains correspondence covering over fifty years, and various aspects of Jones' personal and professional life. General correspondence with Jones' professional and artistic contacts, arranged alphabetically and including a list of correspondents, is found here along with the correspondence of friends and family. The correspondence of Jones' daughters, Kellie and Lisa Jones, makes up the bulk of the family material, although there is also extensive correspondence from jazz musician Marion Brown. This series also holds fan mail and correspondence with Jones' students.
  - General, 1950s-2009
    - List of A-Z Correspondents (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Abel-Bocchino, 1982-2008 (29 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 2 to 30)
    - Bond-Coleman, 1971-2008 (25 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 1 to 25)
    - Community Word Project-Henderson Holmes, 1969-2008 (50 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 1 to 50)
    - Heneghan-Lindner, 1973-2009 (48 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 1 to 48)
    - Loewinsohn-Obermayr, 1978-2009 (45 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 1 to 45)
    - Obermayr-Ramsey, 1959-2008 (30 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 1 to 30)
    - Randall-Shepp, 1977-2008 (35 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 1 to 35)
    - Sherman-Wachtel, 1966-2009 (Box 8, Folder 1 to 45)
    - Walker-Zimmerman, 1966-2009 (Box 9, Folder 1 to 23)
  - Friends and Family, 1940s-2009
    - Kellie
      - General, 1967-2008 (Box 9, Folder 24)
      - General, 1974-1994 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Childhood and College, 1967-2000 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Professional, 1984-2004 (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Family, 2007-2008 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Lisa, 1971-2009
      - General, 1972-2009, (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Childhood and College, 1971-1983 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Friends, 1996-2009 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Marriage--Stephan Dweck, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Professional, 1983-1995 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Zoe, 2006 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Brown, Marion, 1964-2001
      - General, 1964-2001 (2 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 4 to 5)
      - Art, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Photographs, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Sheet Music, 1974-1976 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Cohen Family, 1940s-2009 (10 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 9 to 18)
    - Colvin, Marilyn and Family, 1970s-2006 (3 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 19 to 21)
    - Colvin, Marilyn and Family, 1975-1981 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Dawson, Fielding and Susan Maldovan, 1986-2009 (5 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 2 to 6)
    - Fenichel, Susan and Paul, 1986-2008 (2 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 7 to 8)
    - King Family, 1977-2009 (4 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 9 to 12)
    - King Family, 1977-2009 (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Wachtel, Chuck, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Neighbors, 2009 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - White, Dorothy, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Fan Mail, 1973-2005 (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 6 to 7)
  - Student Correspondence, 1994-2009
    - General, 2005-2009 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Choi to Westmoreland, 1994-2007 (16 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 9 to 24)
- Series II: Writings, 1956-2009
  Contained in this series are research materials, notes, drafts, and extra-textual material for all of Jones' major writings. The material has been grouped into five subseries, reflecting the scope of Jones' career as a writer. The series primarily contains drafts, in various stages, of works in the various genres in which Jones wrote—this includes non-fiction memoir, particularly How I Became Hettie Jones, reviews, fiction, poetry, and children's and young adult literature. Many reviews of Jones' writings, and a number of academic studies of Jones, her work, and her role in the Beat Generation can also be found here. Additionally, there is material pertaining to Jones' many speeches, lectures, literary readings—including drafts and event listings and flyers—and grant and fellowship proposals. Issues of Yugen, the little magazine Jones edited with her former husband LeRoi Jones/Amiri Baraka, have been included and provide an example of Jones' editorial work. When possible, the original order and folder titles have been preserved.
  - Subseries II.1: How I Became Hettie Jones, 1983-2007
    The bulk of this subseries is made up of approximately ten complete typescript drafts and galleys, some with handwritten corrections. Also included are research materials, original book proposals, copyright and royalty information, and correspondence relating to the editing and publishing of the book. Finally, this subseries holds reviews and publicity relevant to its post-publication history and reception. The original order and folder titles have been preserved.
    - Notes, 1980s (4 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 25 to 28)
    - Articles/Other Materials, 1980s (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Book Proposal, 1980s (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence,1983-2001
      - German Edition, 1993-1997 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Editorial, 1983-1991 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - Book Report Effort, 1994-1996 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - Virago Press--UK Edition, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Fan Mail, 1990-2001 (2 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 7 to 8)
      - Judith Leonard Productions, 1990-1995 (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - Itkoff, Jones, Hoffman, 1995-2000 (Box 14, Folder 10)
      - Hoffman, Berenice, 1997 (2 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 11 to 12)
    - Fuzzy Bunny, 1998-2001 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Television Rights, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Permissions,1986-1989 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Publicity, 1988-1990
      - Advance Comments, 1988-1989 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - General, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Covers, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Party, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Reviews, 1990-2005 (4 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 5 to 8)
    - Reviews, 1958-1991 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Royalties, 1990-2007
      - Grove Edition, 1996-2007 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Dutton & Viking and Penguin Editions, 1990-1994 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Floppy Disks, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Drafts, 1986-1991
      - Early, 1986 (1 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - Early, 1986 (2 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Draft 1, undated (2 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 2 to 3)
      - Draft 2, undated (2 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 4 to 5)
      - Draft 3, undated (1 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - Draft 3, undated (2 of 2) (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Draft 4--Corrections, 1989 (2 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 2 to 3)
      - Galleys, 1990 (3 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 4 to 6)
      - Galleys, 1990 (4 of 4) (Box 18, Folder 1 to 4)
      - Sample Pages, circa. 1990 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Returned Drafts, 1991 (3 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 6 to 8)
  - Subseries II.2: Poetry, 1950s-2008
    This subseries contains poetry from the breadth of Jones' writing career. The bulk of this subseries comprises those poems which have been published as poetry collections, and includes complete typescript drafts of Jones' books: All Told, Drive, Doing 70, For Four Hetties, and Having Been Her. Also here are correspondence, publicity, reviews and other articles pertaining to the individual books. Jones' uncollected poems, listed here, following Jones' alphabetical arrangement and labeling, as "Poetry A-Z," running from the 1950s to the 2000s, also form a major component of this subseries. In addition a small amount of occasional poems, poetry notes, and poetry written for grant submissions is here. This subseries has been arranged according to Jones' original order.
    - Poems in Collections, 1992-2006
      - Witness to Dissent, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - "Pride will Fear Wit", 1993 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Women of the Bowery, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Wildflowers, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Vent Your Inspiration, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - "Home", 1991 (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - Arts for Peace Festival, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - All Told, 2000-2004
      - Contracts and Permissions, 2002-2003 (Box 18, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence, 2000-2003 (Box 18, Folder 18)
      - Table of Contents, undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
      - Publicity, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 20)
      - Reviews, 2003-2004 (Box 18, Folder 21)
      - Royalties, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 22)
      - Cover Mockups, undated (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Doing 70, 2006-2008
      - Drafts, 2006 (2 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 24)
      - Alternative Drafts, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Book Party, 2007 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - NYT Book Review, 2007 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Hanging Loose Press Catalog and Uncorrected Proof, 2007-2008 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - "The Second Person"--Promotional Poem Printout, undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Drive, 1995-1999
      - Alternative Titles, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Comments from Chuck Wachtel, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence and Contract, 1996-1999 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Manuscript and Cover Proofs,1998 (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - Norma Farber First Book Award, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - Party, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - Publicity, 1997-1998 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - Reviews and Articles, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - Royalties, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - For Four Hetties, 1985-1995
      - Drafts and Proofs, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 15)
      - Research Material, 1985-1991 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Having Been Her, 1979-1981
      - Typescript Draft, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 17)
      - "The Indian Party"--Drafts, undated (Box 19, Folder 18)
      - "The X-Ray Technician" Drafts, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Christmas Poems, 1999-2009 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Poetry for Grant Submission, 1980s (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Poetry Notes, undated (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Poetry A-Z, 1950s-2004
      - "A Beautiful Day"--"A Little Light Verse for Helene", 1950s-2002 (Box 19, Folder 23)
      - "All the Beautiful Days"--"Back", 1957-1989 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - "Back on the Brooklyn-Queens Expressway"--"Cold Snaps", 1950s-2002 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - "Color"--"The Doorman Has Been Paroled", 1960s-2004 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - "Double Decker"--"Fear", 1967-2001 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - "The Female Equivalent"--"Generations", 1956-2000s (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - "Genuflection to Petty Officer First Class"--"Gramma’s Tears", circa 1960s-2003 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - "Had He a Need of Roots"--"Improper Shutdown Detected", 1959-1990s (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - "In all that Darkness"--"It was narrative", 1960s-2002 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - "Jam"--"Living on Air", 1960s-1999 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - "Look at How We Live"--"Mrs. Shandho Says", 1968-1991 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - "Muscular Crepuscular"--"Not", 1963-1996 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - "(Not) Absolutely the Last Love Poem"--"The Parks on the Peripheries", 1980-1999 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - "Past Life Between"--"Preservation", 1957-2001 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - "Privilege"--"Ruby My Dear", 1979-2005 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - "Salidin’s Crossin"--"She", 1966-1997 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - "She Tells the Young Woman"--"Starting Here", 1957-2003 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - "Stock Market"--"This is For Hettie Barnes", 1970s-1993 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - "This is For Hetty Fox"--"The Time, the time, the time", 1950s-1988 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - "Tonight the Sky is Purple"--"Vito!", 1960s-2003 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - "Wait What’s This"--"Well here comes the doctor", 1956-1991 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - "What a Loud Voice"--"Women in Black", 1956-1995 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - "Woodshedding"--"You know I watched…", 1995 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Subseries II.3: Prose, 1955-2009
    Jones' published and unpublished non-fiction prose, including essays, reviews, editorial work, lectures, speeches, and public reading listings are held in this subseries. The material in this subseries, unless otherwise noted, is arranged according to Jones' original order.
    Included within this series are the manuscripts for an unpublished short story collection, comprised of previously published material, entitled In Care of Worth Auto Parts, as well as typescripts of a number of published and unpublished short stories; material pertaining to Jones' essays—particularly her contribution to the Rolling Stone Beat Book and Women of the Beat Generation, as well as material relating to Jones' essay, co-written with daughter Lisa Jones, "Mama's White"; and typescript drafts of Jones' numerous book reviews, and a small amount of editorial work not associated with Yugen or Totem Press.
    Also here is material from Jones' history of runaway slaves, From Midnight to Dawn, including a complete typescript as well as revisions to individual chapters is here as well as drafts of Jones book, written with Rita Marley, entitled No Woman No Cry. Many the drafts, which range from first complete drafts to corrected drafts and chapter outlines written by Rita Marley include Marley's handwritten corrections. In addition, there are research notes, multiple chapter revisions and expansions or additions to chapters, an original book proposal, book reviews, contracts, and correspondence with editors and Marley, and photographs from the book. Finally, there is audio material, including digital sound files and cassette tape interviews with Marley, as well as typed transcriptions of these interviews. Because the material associated with No Woman No Cry was received in no discernible order, it has been arranged alphabetically.
    istings and text for Jones' numerous speeches and readings can also be found within this series. Following Jones' ordering, both speeches and readings have been arranged by date. Also in this subseries are drafts of grant proposals written by Jones. Finally, there are items, in various mediums, about Jones, and her role in the Beat and Downtown literary movement—including academic theses and dissertations, articles, audio, television, radio, and film.
    - In Care of Worth Auto Parts, 1981-2000
      - Draft, 1998-2000 (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1981-1999 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Grant, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Published Short Stories, 1982-1997
      - "The Big Fish", 1997 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - "Enough of This," undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - "How She Beat the Bogeyman," undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - "The Ironing Board," circa 1980s (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - "Minor Surgery," 1982 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - "This Time It Was Different at the Airport", undated (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Unpublished Short Stories, undated
      - "Cross Country Parkway", undated (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - "Disintegration," undated (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - "Going To Jail", undated (Box 24, Folder 12)
      - "How I Learned About Losing," undated (Box 24, Folder 13)
      - "How She Recognized Her Last Fling When She Found It," undated (Box 24, Folder 14)
      - "In Memory of Music", undated (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - "Just Try to Go Somewhere You Can’t", undated (Box 24, Folder 16)
      - "The Making of a Writer", undated (Box 24, Folder 17)
      - Untitled, undated (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Rolling Stone Beat Book, 1998-1999
      - Correspondence--Holly George Warren, 1998-1999 (Box 24, Folder 19)
      - "Babes in Boyland" and Bancroft Library Speech--Drafts, 1998-1999 (Box 24, Folder 20)
      - Notes, 1999 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Other Genres--Unpublished, 1955-1990
      - "Hers" Column, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 22)
      - Grad School Plays, 1955-1956 (Box 24, Folder 23)
      - Romance Novel, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - "Occasional Writing and Miscellaneous Starts," 1957-1980s
      - Journal Fragments, 1957 (Box 24, Folder 25)
      - Occasional Journal/Notes, 1970s (Box 24, Folder 26)
      - Occasional Journal, 1980s (Box 24, Folder 27)
      - Miscellaneous Starts, undated (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - From Midnight to Dawn, 1980s-2007
      - Complete Drafts, 1980s-2004 (6 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 1 to 6)
      - Complete Drafts, 2004 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Chapter Drafts, 2004-2005
        - Introduction, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
        - Preface, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
        - "Dawn and ‘Uncle Tom’", undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
        - "Wilberforce", 2004 (Box 26, Folder 5)